<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Jack Hayes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Jack Hayes</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:07:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Venting</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vents/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:07:09 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vents/</guid>
            <description>Summary Clickbait title, couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the obvious one! This page is just a collection of details on the vents in my house for future Jack.
Vents (Exhaust Units) Exhaust units are the devices that pull air out of a room (manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s nomenclature). There are three vents in the house. These are located in the kitchen, downstairs toilet and upstairs bathroom.
They all look similar but are actually different variants, all designed by Aereco.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Clickbait title, couldn&rsquo;t resist the obvious one! This page is just a collection of details on the vents in my house for future Jack.</p>
<h2 id="vents--exhaust-units">Vents (Exhaust Units)</h2>
<p>Exhaust units are the devices that pull air out of a room (manufacturer&rsquo;s nomenclature).
There are three vents in the house. These are located in the kitchen, downstairs toilet and upstairs bathroom.</p>
<p>They all look similar but are actually different variants, all designed by Aereco.
There is a comparison table located <a href="https://www.aereco.ie/products/exhaust-units-ie/bxc-2/#characteristics">here</a>.</p>
<p>Just in case it disappears later, the gist of it is:</p>
<ul>
<li>The bathroom ones have a boost feature when a person is present.</li>
<li>The kitchen and bathroom check for humidity (I guess the thinking is that a downstairs toilet won&rsquo;t have much water vapour anyways).</li>
<li>The kitchen one needs to be reset after the powerdown event.</li>
<li>The kitchen one&rsquo;s presence sensor lights up green, unlike the others (as a way of communicating diagnostics, whereas the sensor is used in the other variants and doesn&rsquo;t light up).</li>
</ul>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Location</th>
<th>Type</th>
<th>Part Number</th>
<th>Humidity Sensitive</th>
<th>Boost Airflow</th>
<th>Boost Airflow based on presence detection</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Kitchen</td>
<td>BXC^2 hps</td>
<td>BXC1898</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>N</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Upstairs Bathroom</td>
<td>BXC^2 hpd</td>
<td>BXC1908</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>Y</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Downstairs Toilet</td>
<td>BXC^2 pd</td>
<td>BXC1905</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>Y</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<ul>
<li>Troubleshooting guide for the <a href="/vents/bxchps-beeping-troubleshooting-noise.pdf">BXC^2 hps model</a> (about the beeping).</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="exhaust-fan">Exhaust Fan</h2>
<p>The exhaust fan is made by Aereco also, a <a href="https://www.aereco.ie/products/exhaust-fans-ie/v4a-premium/">V4A336</a> (The V4A Premium for 230V).</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/vents/TF4496_E_V4Apremium_display-4.pdf">Installation Guide</a></li>
<li><a href="/vents/FLY337GB_v4_display-4.pdf">Product Booklet</a></li>
<li><a href="/vents/TF4540_C_display-1.pdf">Replacement Kit Booklet</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="future-stuff">Future Stuff</h2>
<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s a way to measure pressure using a manometer over these vents I believe, so that might be interesting to try in the future.</li>
<li>I think the vents all make their way up to the attic, where there&rsquo;s a much larger exhuast, but I&rsquo;m not completely sure on that yet.
<ul>
<li>At the same time, we also have a vent over the hob but that&rsquo;s venting a different way I think.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>I think these vents might also have features for Co2 but I&rsquo;m not sure yet.</li>
<li>The vent doors are adjustable I believe, so you can increase the amount of venting.
<ul>
<li>(This could be a trade-off of heat loss vs stagnant air I think, not explored yet).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links</h2>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Emacs modifications</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs/</guid>
            <description>Summary This is a list of some niggles and how I deal with them as a reference.
Deleting the first ‘x’ characters from every line in a region with Emacs. You use your mark tool (‘C-Spc’) to highlight a box area and then use the command ‘C-x r k’ to remove this square/rectangle.
Don’t worry about the mark tool highlighting the edges of lines in between, they won’t be clipped.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>This is a list of some niggles and how I deal with them as a reference.</p>
<h2 id="deleting-the-first-x-characters-from-every-line-in-a-region-with-emacs-dot">Deleting the first ‘x’ characters from every line in a region with Emacs.</h2>
<p>You use your mark tool (‘C-Spc’) to highlight a box area and then use the command ‘C-x r k’ to remove this square/rectangle.</p>
<p>Don’t worry about the mark tool highlighting the edges of lines in between, they won’t be clipped.</p>
<p><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/15929872/deleting-the-first-x-characters-from-every-line-in-a-region-with-emacs">Link</a></p>
<h2 id="handy-way-to-append-a-flag-to-the-end-of-a-line-dot">Handy way to append a flag to the end of a line.</h2>
<p>Command: M-&lt; M-x replace-regexp RET $ RET a RET</p>
<p>This will place an ‘a’ at the end of all lines. The $ matches the end-of-line character.</p>
<p>Also one of the other answers shows how to use key-macros so could be handy later.</p>
<h2 id="reload-configurations-without-restarting-emacs">Reload configurations without restarting Emacs</h2>
<p>A quick way to reload your .emacs after making changes, to save a restart.</p>
<p>``` html
// M-x eval-buffer
```</p>
<p><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/167705/reload-configurations-without-restarting-emacs">Link</a></p>
<h2 id="finding-location-of-dot-emacs-file-dot">Finding location of .emacs file.</h2>
<p>C-h v &lsquo;user-init-file&rsquo;</p>
<p><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/864892/how-do-i-find-which-emacs-file-has-been-loaded">Link</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>House Manuals</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/manuals/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/manuals/</guid>
            <description>Summary It seems like it might be a good idea to group all the manuals for various appliances together.
Kitchen Heat Pump Living Room </description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>It seems like it might be a good idea to group all the manuals for various appliances together.</p>
<h2 id="kitchen">Kitchen</h2>
<h3 id="heat-pump">Heat Pump</h3>
<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="living-room">Living Room</h2>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Using Org-Mode with Hugo</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-org/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-org/</guid>
            <description>Summary This page is a summary of stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about using org-mode with Hugo to publish webpages. It is still very much in flux.
Starting Points I use emacs a fair bit and org-mode a bit so I&amp;rsquo;m interested in using an org-mode flow. Because I use hugo to generate my website at the moment, use of a package called ox-hugo seemed the most convenient.
Links Some resources I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far are:</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>This page is a summary of stuff I&rsquo;ve learnt about using org-mode with Hugo to publish webpages.
It is still very much in flux.</p>
<h2 id="starting-points">Starting Points</h2>
<p>I use emacs a fair bit and org-mode a bit so I&rsquo;m interested in using an org-mode flow.
Because I use hugo to generate my website at the moment, use of a package called <a href="https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/">ox-hugo</a> seemed the most convenient.</p>
<h3 id="links">Links</h3>
<p>Some resources I&rsquo;ve found so far are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://andreyor.st/posts/2022-10-16-my-blogging-setup-with-emacs-and-org-mode/">Andrey Listopadov&rsquo;s setup</a>
<ul>
<li>Got me up and running initially.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://diego.codes/post/blogging-with-org/">Diego Vicente&rsquo;s setup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lucidmanager.org/productivity/create-websites-with-org-mode-and-hugo/">Dr. Peter Prevos&rsquo; setup</a>
<ul>
<li>Handy details on front matter.</li>
<li>Nice snippet on setting up a lastmod timestamp.</li>
<li>Note that he doesn&rsquo;t use ox-hugo.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-a-new-post">Adding a new post</h2>
<ol>
<li>Go to the home directory and add a new file &lsquo;post_XX.org&rsquo;.</li>
<li>Add a preamble of #commands that can be copied from an old post.</li>
<li>Write your post.</li>
<li>Use of the command C-c, C-e, H, H.
<ul>
<li>This invokes ox-hugo that will generate the markdown file.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Go to a terminal and invoke &lsquo;hugo server -D&rsquo; from the home directory.</li>
<li>Marvel at the results located at &lsquo;https://localhost:1313&rsquo;.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="adding-images-and-pdfs-dot">Adding Images and PDFs.</h2>
<ol>
<li>Put the images you&rsquo;re interested in, in the <em>static</em> directory.</li>
<li>Then you can reference them using the file: prefix and various square brackets.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="links">Links</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/doc/image-links/">Ox-Hugo Image Links</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-tables">Adding Tables</h2>
<p>Firstly we can add a table by use of comma seperated values.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://orgmode.org/worg/org-tutorials/tables.html">https://orgmode.org/worg/org-tutorials/tables.html</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="themes">Themes</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m currently using the <a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng/">hello-friend-ng</a> theme.</p>
<h2 id="things-to-figure-out">Things to figure out</h2>
<ol>
<li>How do I add little hover notes?</li>
<li>How do I change the theme properly?</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Setting up Shelly H&amp;T Plus with Home Assistant</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/shelly-handt/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 20:54:50 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/shelly-handt/</guid>
            <description>Introduction I bought two Shelly H&amp;amp;T Plus (version 3) devices a couple of months ago. The reason for choosing them at the time was because:
They had a legible screen. The company seemed to have a reasonable reputation. There was an option to use the devices without their own apps (as in, local use only). WiFi as a protocol seemed cleaner at the time, less to go wrong. (In the meantime, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is so true anymore).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I bought two <a href="https://www.shelly.com/en-ie/products/product-overview/shelly-plus-h-and-t">Shelly H&amp;T Plus</a> (version 3) devices a couple of months ago.
The reason for choosing them at the time was because:</p>
<ul>
<li>They had a legible screen.</li>
<li>The company seemed to have a reasonable reputation.</li>
<li>There was an option to use the devices without their own apps (as in, local use only).</li>
<li>WiFi as a protocol seemed cleaner at the time, less to go wrong.
<ul>
<li>(In the meantime, I don&rsquo;t know if this is so true anymore).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>
<p>Just some notes for myself next time I have to set these up..</p>
<ol>
<li>Pressing the button on the back for 5 seconds puts it into a setup mode where the device is a WiFI Access Point.
<ul>
<li>This means that you can connect to it directly via WiFi (as in, it will show up in your list of WiFi networks to connect to).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>When this happens, go to the IP address 192.168.33.1.</li>
<li>From here, you then have all sorts of options. In our case, we want to turn on an option called &lsquo;Outbound websocket&rsquo;.</li>
<li>You will give it an address like: ws://192.XXXXX:8123/api/shelly/ws with SSL connectivity set up and a * for the cert.
<ul>
<li>(There&rsquo;s some pickiness here on the capitalization I think, looking at other folks complaints online so keep all lowercase, just in case it&rsquo;s an issue).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>When you make changes on the webserver, you&rsquo;ll often have to reboot the temperature sensor, so just be aware of that.
<ul>
<li>Also, because the device goes into sleep mode often, you&rsquo;ll quite likely have to press the button on the device to get these changes to be worked on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Once that&rsquo;s all done, going back to the server webpage, it should tell you that it&rsquo;s all good now.</li>
<li>Then you go to the Home Assistant webpage and it should add the entity automatically.
<ul>
<li>Again, a restart of Home Assistant seemed necessary here.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>What I know about Ecodan ASHPs</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ecodan/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ecodan/</guid>
            <description>Summary The following is a meandering post on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about heat pumps (and more specifically the Ecodan range from Mistubishi) and some handy resources I&amp;rsquo;ve found.
The System The gist of the sytem is shown in the following infographic.
The Outdoor Unit I&amp;rsquo;m using an 5kW Mitsubishi Ecodan Air to Water Heat Pump. It uses R32 as its refrigerant.
There are two sides to every heat pump, the source and the sink.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>The following is a meandering post on what I&rsquo;ve learnt about heat pumps (and more specifically the Ecodan range from Mistubishi) and some handy resources I&rsquo;ve found.</p>
<h2 id="the-system">The System</h2>
<p>The gist of the sytem is shown in the following infographic.</p>
<figure><a href="/heatpumps/infographic.jpeg"><img src="/heatpumps/infographic.jpeg"></a>
</figure>

<h3 id="the-outdoor-unit">The Outdoor Unit</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m using an 5kW Mitsubishi Ecodan Air to Water Heat Pump. It uses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Difluoromethane">R32</a> as its refrigerant.</p>
<p>There are two sides to every heat pump, the source and the sink. One can think of the source (air passing through the fan outdoors) as the input and the sink as the output (our radiators, etc).
In this case, our source is Air and our sink is Water.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/heatpumps/Ecodan_PUZ-WM50VHA_Monobloc_Air_Source_Heat_Pump_Product_Information_Sheet.pdf">Ecodan PUZ-WM50VHA Information Sheet</a></li>
<li><a href="/heatpumps/EcodanPUZ-WM_50-60-85-112_V_H-A_A_Installation_Manual__BH79D849H02UK_.pdf">Ecodan PUZ-WM Installation Guide</a></li>
<li><a href="/heatpumps/Ecodan_PUZ-WM_50-60-85-112_V_H-A_A_Service_Manual__OCH727A_.pdf">Ecodan PUZ-WV50VHA (OCH727) Service Manual</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="the-indoor-unit--cylinder-unit">The Indoor Unit (Cylinder Unit)</h3>
<p>Judging by the label on the unit, this an EHPT17X-VM2DR1.UK model. The 17 in the title means that it has a 170 litre DHW (Domestic Hot Water) tank.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/heatpumps/Ecodan_EHPT20X-MHEDWR1_Service_Manual__OCH714E_.pdf">Ecodan EHPT17X-VM2DR1.UK Service Manual</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="map-of-the-plumbing">Map of the Plumbing</h3>
<p>The following image is a map of the pipework above the cylinder unit, with labels.
Some of this is based off the labels attached to the pipes and other parts are guesswork.</p>
<h4 id="dhw-details">DHW Details</h4>
<ul>
<li>There are two feeds of water coming in.
<ul>
<li>One of these is labelled cold; I think this comes from the tank in the attic.
<ul>
<li>(It could be coming from mains but I don&rsquo;t think it is because it&rsquo;s coming down from the ceiling so seems like an unlikely path).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The other one is labelled hot. I think this is a return path from the hot water that orginates from the cylinder unit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>These mix together and go into the heat pump.
<ul>
<li>There is also a header tank here and an overflow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>These then come back out and go out again towards all three of the hot water taps and the shower.</li>
</ul>
<figure><a href="/heatpumps/heatpump_map_1.jpeg"><img src="/heatpump_map_1.jpeg"></a>
</figure>

<h4 id="radiator-details">Radiator Details</h4>
<ul>
<li>Starting from the left, I think these are two return paths for the radiators.</li>
<li>They combine together and then enter a filter before going into the unit.
<ul>
<li>(The filter is a <a href="https://fernox.com/product/tf1-sigma-filter/">Fernox TF1 Sigma Filter</a>, which has a 10 year warranty).</li>
<li><a href="/heatpumps/62417-TF1-Sigma-Filter.pdf">TF1 Sigma Filter 28mm Data Sheet</a>
<ul>
<li>This data sheet shows how to clean the filter also.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The heated up fluid then comes out of the cylinder unit, from the second pipe from the left.
<ul>
<li>There are two tap points here with a valve between.
<ul>
<li>I think this is to allow for an underfloor heating loop to be added on conveniently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>This hot line then goes up and branches into two separate lines.</li>
<li>Each line has a motorized control valve on it.
<ul>
<li>(Adjusting the thermostats in the rooms seems to have an effect on these, lighting them up).</li>
<li><a href="/heatpumps/2023-04-27_V22_P-FP_DS_PK_Email.pdf">EPH V222PW Installation &amp; Technical Spec Document</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="other-details">Other Details</h4>
<h2 id="adding-a-smart-sensor">Adding a smart sensor</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s possible to add a smart sensor to this heating system. The model number I used was 587IF-E.</p>
<p>When I was trying to source this, there was confusion online about the fact that there are multiple variants.
It seems like there&rsquo;s a different part number for Austrialian models (or something).</p>
<p>I bought mine on <a href="https://www.ebay.ie/itm/284060037125">eBay</a> and it seemed to work fine.</p>
<p>For installation, I used the following videos:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZj4t4kwYVQ">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZj4t4kwYVQ</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1wABPBAWK8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1wABPBAWK8</a></li>
</ul>
<figure><a href="/heatpumps/heatpump_sensor_1.png"><img src="/heatpump_sensor_1.png"></a>
</figure>

<h2 id="diagnostics">Diagnostics</h2>
<h3 id="pressure-gauge">Pressure Gauge</h3>
<ul>
<li>Previously I had a slight weep in the system. There&rsquo;s a gauge that indicates the pressure of the system.</li>
<li>From talking to the plumber and heat pump service guy, keeping it in the range of 1 to 2 bar is what you&rsquo;re looking for, they advise.</li>
</ul>
<figure><a href="/heatpumps/heatpump_gauge_28jun24_1.jpeg"><img src="/heatpump_gauge_28jun24_1.jpeg"></a>
</figure>

<figure><a href="/heatpumps/heatpump_gauge_28jun24_2.jpeg"><img src="/heatpump_gauge_28jun24_2.jpeg"></a>
</figure>

<h2 id="links">Links</h2>
<ul>
<li>The book <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Heat-Pumps-Home-John-Cantor/dp/1785007793/ref=sr_1_3?crid=14CXTV81MAL5A&dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.v79c5G2CcnKI1ma3zMB0zVfWk5pPPkDXTLfbsC-64gLOs0P7-k5QmsNHMl6MvnMme-zdApiBmqPOIBYYy1njTr-ooDyW2xDh2LObpWiuChLoh3gfUWpgvm9RRgTBqqgLw94QgnSSTsMZa9DYmIlriGowM4sAgE5DqFHesfkOyMCkcw0z1vzvn7H0Omk-lEDT7lJ9Zan8qhScqMGUCUnn3gLC_L5l8WvdtLHKgKVvkpA.BLOOjOyIAwjk3ynCdH0Zj3D8ZMmsLSbQhqrCL1Z7tYQ&dib_tag=se&keywords=heat+pumps+for+the+home&qid=1719574691&sprefix=heat+pumps+for+the+%2Caps%2C72&sr=8-3">Heat Pumps for the Home</a> was pretty good.
<ul>
<li>It actually includes a lot of systems that use Ecodans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
