<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Jack&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Jack&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:44:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Vents</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vents/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:44:36 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vents/</guid>
            <description>Introduction There are three vents in the house. These are located in the kitchen, downstairs toilet and upstairs bathroom.
They all look similar but are actually different variants, all designed by Aereco. There is a comparison table located here: https://www.aereco.ie/products/exhaust-units-ie/bxc-2/#characteristics
Just in case it disappears later, the gist is:
The bathroom ones have a boost feature when a person is present. The kitchen and bathroom check for humidity (I guess the downstairs toilet won&amp;rsquo;t have much water vapour anyways).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>There are three vents in the house. These are located in the kitchen, downstairs toilet and upstairs bathroom.</p>
<p>They all look similar but are actually different variants, all designed by Aereco.
There is a comparison table located here: <a href="https://www.aereco.ie/products/exhaust-units-ie/bxc-2/#characteristics">https://www.aereco.ie/products/exhaust-units-ie/bxc-2/#characteristics</a></p>
<p>Just in case it disappears later, the gist is:</p>
<ul>
<li>The bathroom ones have a boost feature when a person is present.</li>
<li>The kitchen and bathroom check for humidity (I guess the downstairs toilet won&rsquo;t have much water vapour anyways).</li>
<li>The kitchen one needs to be reset after the powerdown event.</li>
<li>The kitchen one&rsquo;s presence sensor lights up green, unlike the others (as a way of communicating diagnostics, whereas the sensor is used in the other variants).</li>
</ul>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Location</th>
<th>Type</th>
<th>Part Number</th>
<th>Humidity Sensitive</th>
<th>Boost Airflow</th>
<th>Boost Airflow based on presence detection</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Kitchen</td>
<td>BXC^2 hps</td>
<td>BXC1898</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>N</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Upstairs Bathroom</td>
<td>BXC^2 hpd</td>
<td>BXC1908</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>Y</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Downstairs Toilet</td>
<td>BXC^2 pd</td>
<td>BXC1905</td>
<td>N</td>
<td>Y</td>
<td>Y</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="other-details">Other Details</h2>
<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s a way to measure pressure using a manometer over these vents I believe, so that might be interesting to try in the future.</li>
<li>I think the vents all make their way up to the attic, where there&rsquo;s a much larger exhuast, but I&rsquo;m not completely sure on that yet.
<ul>
<li>At the same time, we also have a vent over the hob but that&rsquo;s venting a different way I think.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>I think these vents might also have features for Co2 but I&rsquo;m not sure yet.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Using Org-Mode with Hugo</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-org/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-org/</guid>
            <description>Summary This page is a summary of stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about using org-mode with Hugo to publish webpages. It is still very much in flux as of &amp;lt;2024-06-28 Fri&amp;gt;.
Starting Points I use emacs a fair bit and org-mode a bit so I&amp;rsquo;m interested in using an org-mode flow. Because I use hugo to generate my website at the moment, use of a package called ox-hugo seemed the most convenient.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>This page is a summary of stuff I&rsquo;ve learnt about using org-mode with Hugo to publish webpages.
It is still very much in flux as of <!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;2024-06-28 Fri&gt;<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->.</p>
<h2 id="starting-points">Starting Points</h2>
<p>I use emacs a fair bit and org-mode a bit so I&rsquo;m interested in using an org-mode flow.
Because I use hugo to generate my website at the moment, use of a package called <a href="https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/">ox-hugo</a> seemed the most convenient.</p>
<p>Some resources I&rsquo;ve found so far are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://andreyor.st/posts/2022-10-16-my-blogging-setup-with-emacs-and-org-mode/">https://andreyor.st/posts/2022-10-16-my-blogging-setup-with-emacs-and-org-mode/</a>
<ul>
<li>Got me up and running initially.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://diego.codes/post/blogging-with-org/">https://diego.codes/post/blogging-with-org/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://lucidmanager.org/productivity/create-websites-with-org-mode-and-hugo/">https://lucidmanager.org/productivity/create-websites-with-org-mode-and-hugo/</a>
<ul>
<li>Handy details on front matter.</li>
<li>Nice snippet on setting up a lastmod timestamp.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-a-new-post">Adding a new post</h2>
<ol>
<li>Go to the home directory and add a new file &lsquo;post_XX.org&rsquo;.</li>
<li>Add a preamble of #commands that can be copied from an old post.</li>
<li>Write your post.</li>
<li>Use of the command C-c, C-e, H, H.
<ul>
<li>This invokes ox-hugo that will generate the markdown file.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Go to a terminal and invoke &lsquo;hugo server -D&rsquo; from the home directory.</li>
<li>Marvel at the results located at &lsquo;https://localhost:1313&rsquo;.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="adding-images">Adding Images</h2>
<p>This was the first stumbling block for me.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ox-hugo.scripter.co/doc/image-links/">Ox-Hugo Image Links</a>
<ul>
<li>Reading over this, put the images you&rsquo;re interested in, in the <em>static</em> directory.</li>
<li>Then you can reference them using the file: prefix and various square brackets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="adding-tables">Adding Tables</h2>
<p>Firstly we can add a table by use of comma seperated values.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://orgmode.org/worg/org-tutorials/tables.html">https://orgmode.org/worg/org-tutorials/tables.html</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="things-to-figure-out">Things to figure out</h2>
<ol>
<li>How do I add little hover notes?</li>
<li>How do I change the theme properly?</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>What I know about Ecodan ASHPs</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ecodan/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 21:14:58 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ecodan/</guid>
            <description>Introduction The following is a meandering post on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about heat pumps (and more specifically the Ecodan range from Mistubishi).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>The following is a meandering post on what I&rsquo;ve learnt about heat pumps (and more specifically the Ecodan range from Mistubishi).</p>
<figure><a href="/heatpump_map_1.jpeg"><img src="/heatpump_map_1.jpeg"></a>
</figure>

]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Setting up Shelly H&amp;T Plus with Home Assistant</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/shelly-handt/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 20:54:50 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/shelly-handt/</guid>
            <description>Introduction I bought two Shelly H&amp;amp;T Plus (version 3) devices a couple of months ago. The reason for choosing them at the time was because:
They had a legible screen. The company seemed to have a reasonable reputation. There was an option to use the devices without their own apps (as in, local use only). WiFi as a protocol seemed cleaner at the time, less to go wrong. (In the meantime, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is so true anymore).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I bought two <a href="https://www.shelly.com/en-ie/products/product-overview/shelly-plus-h-and-t">Shelly H&amp;T Plus</a> (version 3) devices a couple of months ago.
The reason for choosing them at the time was because:</p>
<ul>
<li>They had a legible screen.</li>
<li>The company seemed to have a reasonable reputation.</li>
<li>There was an option to use the devices without their own apps (as in, local use only).</li>
<li>WiFi as a protocol seemed cleaner at the time, less to go wrong.
<ul>
<li>(In the meantime, I don&rsquo;t know if this is so true anymore).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>
<p>Just some notes for myself next time I have to set these up..</p>
<ol>
<li>Pressing the button on the back for 5 seconds puts it into a setup mode where the device is a WiFI Access Point.
<ul>
<li>This means that you can connect to it directly via WiFi (as in, it will show up in your list of WiFi networks to connect to).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>When this happens, go to the IP address 192.168.33.1.</li>
<li>From here, you then have all sorts of options. In our case, we want to turn on an option called &lsquo;Outbound websocket&rsquo;.</li>
<li>You will give it an address like: ws://192.XXXXX:8123/api/shelly/ws with SSL connectivity set up and a * for the cert.
<ul>
<li>(There&rsquo;s some pickiness here on the capitalization I think, looking at other folks complaints online so keep all lowercase, just in case it&rsquo;s an issue).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>When you make changes on the webserver, you&rsquo;ll often have to reboot the temperature sensor, so just be aware of that.
<ul>
<li>Also, because the device goes into sleep mode often, you&rsquo;ll quite likely have to press the button on the device to get these changes to be worked on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Once that&rsquo;s all done, going back to the server webpage, it should tell you that it&rsquo;s all good now.</li>
<li>Then you go to the Home Assistant webpage and it should add the entity automatically.
<ul>
<li>Again, a restart of Home Assistant seemed necessary here.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
