<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Hayes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack Hayes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:07:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Venting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:07:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vents/</guid>
      <description>Summary Clickbait title, couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the obvious one! This page is just a collection of details on the vents in my house for future Jack.&#xA;Vents (Exhaust Units) Exhaust units are the devices that pull air out of a room (manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s nomenclature). There are three vents in the house. These are located in the kitchen, downstairs toilet and upstairs bathroom.&#xA;They all look similar but are actually different variants, all designed by Aereco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 10:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Jack.&#xA;The stuff located here is a collection of my learnings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs modifications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emacs/</guid>
      <description>Summary This is a list of some niggles and how I deal with them as a reference.&#xA;Deleting the first ‘x’ characters from every line in a region with Emacs. You use your mark tool (‘C-Spc’) to highlight a box area and then use the command ‘C-x r k’ to remove this square/rectangle.&#xA;Don’t worry about the mark tool highlighting the edges of lines in between, they won’t be clipped.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Org-Mode with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-org/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo-org/</guid>
      <description>Summary This page is a summary of stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about using org-mode with Hugo to publish webpages. It is still very much in flux.&#xA;Starting Points I use emacs a fair bit and org-mode a bit so I&amp;rsquo;m interested in using an org-mode flow. Because I use hugo to generate my website at the moment, use of a package called ox-hugo seemed the most convenient.&#xA;Links Some resources I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far are:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Shelly H&amp;T Plus with Home Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/shelly-handt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 20:54:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/shelly-handt/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I bought two Shelly H&amp;amp;T Plus (version 3) devices a couple of months ago. The reason for choosing them at the time was because:&#xA;They had a legible screen. The company seemed to have a reasonable reputation. There was an option to use the devices without their own apps (as in, local use only). WiFi as a protocol seemed cleaner at the time, less to go wrong. (In the meantime, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is so true anymore).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I know about Ecodan ASHPs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ecodan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ecodan/</guid>
      <description>Summary The following is a meandering post on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt about heat pumps (and more specifically the Ecodan range from Mistubishi).&#xA;Map of the Plumbing Adding a smart sensor It&amp;rsquo;s possible to add a smart sensor to this heating system. The model number I used was 587IF-E.&#xA;When I was trying to source this, there was confusion online about the fact that there are multiple variants. It seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a different part number for Austrialian models (or something).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
